Guide to the Robert Osborn Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Robert Osborn Papers
1929-1994
1949-1994
YCAL MSS 938
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
41.8
165 (boxes) + 94 broadsides, 13 rolls, 1 oversize portfolio, 1 super broadside, 1 art object
The Robert Osborn Papers contain drawings, paintings, posters, correspondence, collages, printed material, clippings, a sketch notebook, a wooden plate, and dolls. Drawings include drawings of Don Quijote, Charlie Chaplin, and drawings for several publications.
Osborn, Robert Chesley, 1904-1994
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Robert Chesley Osborn, 1983-1994.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Broadsides 3-37, 44-60 and 220-259 (artwork): Restricted fragile material. Unavailable until further processing is completed. Consult Access Services for further information.
Rolls 38-43 (artwork): Restricted fragile material. Unavailable until further processing is completed. Consult Access Services for further information.
Boxes 62-64, 200 and 219 (artwork): Restricted fragile material. Unavailable until further processing is completed. Consult Access Services for further information.
Robert Chelsey Osborn (1904-1994)
Robert Osborn was an American satiric cartoonist, illustrator, and author. Osborn identified himself as "a drawer" motivated by political convictions.
Osborn was born on October 26, 1904, in Oshkosh, Wisconsin. He entered the University of Wisconsin in 1923, then transferred to Yale University later the same year. At Yale, Osborn was the art editor of the campus humor magazine The Yale Record. After graduating from Yale in 1928, he studied painting in Rome and Paris, then returned to the United States and taught art and philosophy at the Hotchkiss School in Lakeville, CT. During this time he made the move from painting to caricature.
Osborn enlisted in the Navy when World War II began, hoping to become a pilot. Instead, he was assigned to a special information unit that produced pilot training manuals. He learned the art of speed drawing and began drawing cartoons of an ignorant pilot, "Dilbert the Pilot," who perpetually violated rules of military safety and put himself and his crew at risk. "Dilbert" caught on as a slang term for a sailor who repeatedly made mistakes and later developed into the term of a mistake made by a Navy pilot. Osborn was prolific, creating over 40,000 drawings for training manuals. The character Dilbert was used in educational posters for Navy pilots, appeared in New York Times and LIFE magazine.
In 1946, he left the Navy and a wrote the book, War is No Damn Good!. The book's skull-like depiction of an atomic bomb's mushroom cloud gained Osborn national attention. Following its release, he started to draw political cartoons for Harper's, Fortune, LIFE, House & Garden, and Look, and became a regular contributor to The New Republic. His cartoons frequently depicted politicians such as Senator Joseph McCarthy and several presidents, from Lyndon Baines Johnson through Ronald Reagan. During his lifetime, Osborn wrote and illustrated several of his own books and books by others. He was politically active, most notably in the nuclear disarmament movement.
Osborn continued to draw for the Navy until the late 1980s and his cartoons were published in Naval Aviation News. The character of Dilbert was replaced by a Navy pilot named "Grampaw Pettibone." His drawings of Charles Chaplin were the basis of an art exhibition in 1987 and his work appeared in various exhibitions throughout the country.
Osborn lived in Salisbury, CT with his wife, Elodie, from 1947 until his death on December 20, 1994.
Scope and Contents
The Robert Osborn Papers contain drawings, paintings, posters, correspondence, collages, printed material, clippings, a sketch notebook, a wooden plate, and dolls made by Osborn. Drawings include drawings of Don Quijote, Charlie Chaplin, and drawings for several publications.
Arrangement
Organized into eight acquisitions: I. December 1983. II. October 1991 Acquisition. III. 1992 Acquisitions. IV. November 1993 Acquisition. V. May 1993 Acquisition. VI. December 1994 Acquisition. VII. February 1996 Acquisition. VIII. 1999 Acquisitions.
Material within this collection has been organized by acquisition reflecting the fact that the collection has been acquired in increments over time. Researchers should note that material within each acquisition overlaps with/or relates to material found in other acquisitions. For instance, correspondence and writings can be found in all twenty groupings. In order to locate all relevant material within this collection, researchers will need to consult each acquisition described in the Collection Contents section.
Artists, American -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century; Cartoonists -- United States -- Archives; Illustrators -- 20th Century; Charcoal drawings; Collage; Dolls; Drawings (visual works); Illustrations (layout features); Mixed media; Oil paintings (visual works); Paintings (visual works); Sketches; Sketchbooks; Watercolors (paintings); Artists -- United States -- 20th Century; Authors -- United States -- 20th Century; Cartoonists -- United States -- 20th Century; Illustrators -- United States -- 20th Century; Osborn, Robert Chesley, 1904-1994
- December 1983 Acquisition, 0.21; 1 (box)
  Scope and Contents
  Former call number: Uncat Za File 32.
  - Autograph letter, signed, from Osborn to Yale Library Associates, 1983 November 28 (Box 1)
- October 1991 Acquisition, 10.58; 23 (boxes) + 50 (broadsides) + 1 (super broadside) + 1 (oversized portfolio) + 6 (rolls)
  Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 215.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Broadsides 3-60 (artwork): Restricted fragile material. Unavailable until further processing is completed. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Boxes 62-64 (artwork): Restricted fragile material. Unavailable until further processing is completed. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Contains drawings, paintings, posters, printed material, and dolls. Drawings include drawings of Don Quijote and Charlie Chaplin. The bulk of the acquisition contains unidentified, untitled, and undated drawings and paintings.
  - "Drawings for Houghton Mifflin", undated (Box 2 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings, undated; 3 (Box 2 (Oversize))
  - Restricted fragile
    Restricted fragile material. Unavailable until further processing is completed. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Unidentified drawings, undated (Box 3 (Broadside))
      Restricted fragile material. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Drawings of Don Quijote and Charlie Chaplin, undated (Box 4 (Broadside))
    - Drawings of Don Quijote and Charlie Chaplin, undated (Box 5 (Broadside))
    - Drawings of Don Quijote and Charlie Chaplin, undated (Box 6 (Broadside))
    - Drawings of Don Quijote and Charlie Chaplin, undated (Box 7 (Broadside))
      Restricted fragile material. Consult Access Services for further information..
    - "Faces", undated (Box 8 (Broadside))
    - "Faces", undated (Box 9 (Broadside))
    - "Faces", undated (Box 10 (Broadside))
    - "Faces", undated (Box 11 (Broadside))
    - "Faces", undated (Box 12 (Broadside))
    - "Faces", undated (Box 13 (Broadside))
    - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated (Box 14 (Broadside))
    - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated (Box 15 (Broadside))
    - "Death As a Matador," collage, pastel, 21.5"x58.5", undated (Box 16 (Oversize Portfolio))
    - "Italian Clown," pastel and crayon, 22"x60", 1960 (Box 16 (Oversize Portfolio))
    - "Fool," pastel, 23"x59", 1959 (Box 16 (Oversize Portfolio))
    - "Death As A Matador," collage, 21.5"x58.75", undated (Box 16 (Oversize Portfolio))
    - Unidentified mixed formats, undated (Box 17 (Broadside))
    - Unidentified mixed formats, undated (Box 18 (Broadside))
    - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated (Box 19 (Broadside))
    - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated (Box 20 (Broadside))
    - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated (Box 21 (Broadside))
    - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated (Box 22 (Broadside))
    - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated (Box 23 (Broadside))
    - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated (Box 24 (Broadside))
    - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated (Box 25 (Broadside))
    - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated (Box 26 (Broadside))
    - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated (Box 27 (Broadside))
    - "Tempers and reasoning become maniacal", undated (Box 28 (Broadside))
    - "The pentagon- the kremlin feel confident", undated (Box 29 (Broadside))
    - "The deadly fantasy proceeds", undated (Box 30 (Broadside))
    - "The dogs of war unleashed spring forth", undated (Box 31 (Broadside))
    - "The conflict real... or imagined, heightened", undated (Box 32 (Broadside))
    - "MAN", undated (Box 33 (Broadside))
    - "The generals are confident", undated (Box 34 (Broadside))
    - "And so it begins", undated (Box 35 (Broadside))
    - "To end in animal debris", undated (Box 36 (Broadside))
    - "With the smallest excuse, the male becomes 'wind up combative", undated (Box 37 (Broadside))
    - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated (Box 38 (Roll))
    - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated (Box 39 (Roll))
    - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated (Box 40 (Roll))
    - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated (Box 41 (Roll))
    - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated (Box 42 (Roll))
    - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated (Box 43 (Roll))
    - "The Matador", 1964 (Box 44 (Broadside))
    - Unidentified paintings, undated (Box 45 (Broadside))
    - "James Joyce" and unidentifed drawing, 1970, undated (Box 46 (Broadside))
    - "Westmoreland" and "Calder", undated, 1965 (Box 47 (Broadside))
    - Unidentified paintings, undated (Box 48 (Broadside))
    - "Chill Before Dawn" and unidentified drawings, undated (Box 49 (Broadside))
    - [Bianci Matador] and "Ballet Dancer", undated, 1967 (Box 50 (Broadside))
    - "The Tragic Eye, Garbo", 1974 (Box 51 (Broadside))
    - "On Conflict", undated (Box 52 (Broadside))
    - "On Conflict", undated (Box 53 (Broadside))
    - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated (Box 54 (Broadside))
    - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated (Box 55 (Broadside))
    - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated (Box 56 (Broadside))
    - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated (Box 57 (Broadside))
    - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated (Box 58 (Broadside))
    - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated (Box 59 (Broadside))
    - The William Benton Museum of Art, "Osborn on Conflict" October 9- November 21, 1982, lent by the artist
      - "Man's ID 5 million years later is powerful in its demands", undated (Box 60 (Broadside))
      - "It is EGO (get it for me) oriented", undated (Box 60 (Broadside))
      - "They have the equipment of 10 tons of TN for every person on earth", undated (Box 60 (Broadside))
      - Untitled, undated (Box 60 (Broadside))
      - Untitled, undated (Box 60 (Broadside))
      - "His endlessly doomed friend does not", undated (Box 60 (Broadside))
      - "The black boxes are readied", undated (Box 60 (Broadside))
      - "Our country in Vietnam: The shame of it", undated (Box 60 (Broadside))
      - "Man's progenitor was ferocious", undated (Box 60 (Broadside))
      - "The hit soldier", undated (Box 60 (Broadside))
      - "National flags are rushed forth", undated (Box 60 (Broadside))
  - Unidentified drawing, undated (Box 61 (Broadside oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated; Housed in a custom made package created before the Beinecke Library acquired the papers. (Box 62 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated; Housed in a custom made package created before the Beinecke Library acquired the papers. (Box 63 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated; Housed in a custom made package created before the Beinecke Library acquired the papers. (Box 64 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated; 3 (Box 65 (Oversize))
  - "Dr. Ritchie I presume", undated (Box 66 (Oversize))
  - "Bad luck? My eye!", undated (Box 66 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated; 4 (Box 67 (Oversize))
  - "That's Lady Hatterly's lover!", undated (Box 68 (Oversize))
  - "Here comes Ritchie", undated (Box 68 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated; 2 (Box 69 (Oversize))
  - Drawings, paintings, clippings, and Dilbert posters, undated; 3 (Box 70 (Oversize))
  - Unidentifed drawings and paintings, undated; 3 (Box 71 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated; 2 (Box 72 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated; 2 (Box 73 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated; 4 (Box 74 (Oversize))
  - "Osborn cover materials with comments", undated (Box 75 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated; 3 (Box 75 (Oversize))
  - Drawings and paintings from Beinecke Exhibit "Serious Whimsy", 9 (Box 218 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated; 2 (Box 219 (Oversize))
  - "Cop-out", undated (Box 219 (Oversize))
  - Printed material, undated; 3 (Box 267 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings and paintings, 3 (Box 267 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated; 5 (Box 268 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated; 5 (Box 269 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated; 2 (Box 270 (Oversize))
  - Dilbert posters, undated; 2 (Box 271 (Oversize))
  - Dolls, undated (Box 272 (Oversize))
- 1992 Acquisitions, 0.29; 2 (boxes)
  - April 1992 Acquisition
    Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 298.
    - Correspondence with Charles and Lucie Oliver Nagel, 1985-1987 (Box 76)
  - April 1992 Acquisition
    Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 225.
    - Bill submitted to Industrial Design Magazine for the Industrial Rebinders, in the form of an untitled ink and wash drawing, signed, 1954 (Box 77 (Oversize))
- November 1993 Acquisition, 0.25; 1 (box)
  - "General", undated; 3 (Box 78 (Oversize))
- May 1993 Acquisition, 0.08; 1 (box)
  Former call number: Uncat Za MS 301.
  - Easter greeting to Isabel Wilder, 1993 (Box 79 (Oversize))
- December 1994 Acquisition, 0.25; 1 (box)
  Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 412.
  - "Log of the Spindrift," illustrated by Robert Osborn, undated (Box 80 (Oversize))
- February 1996 Acquisition, 29.84; 123 (boxes) + 53 (Broadsides) + 7 (Rolls)
  Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 475.
  Contains drawings, paintings, correspondence, posters, clippings, collages, a wooden plate, and a sketch notebook.
  Box 200 (artwork): Restricted fragile material. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Correspondence, drawings, and clippings, undated; 11 (Box 81)
  - Wooden plate, undated (Box 82 (Oversize))
  - Correspondence, drawings, and paintings, undated; 14 (Box 83)
  - Correspondence, drawings, and paintings, undated; 6 (Box 84)
  - Drawings of Charlie Chaplin, undated; 3 (Box 85 (Oversize))
  - Horticulture paintings, undated (Box 86 (Oversize))
  - Drawings relating the American Midwest, undated; 3 (Box 87 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated; 2 (Box 87 (Oversize))
  - Drawings of American flag, undated (Box 88)
  - Page stats of entire book, undated (Box 88)
  - Grampaw Pettibone drawings, undated; 3 (Box 89 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified paintings, undated; 3 (Box 90 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated; 3 (Box 91 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated; 2 (Box 92 (Oversize))
  - Drawings for the Saturday Evening Post, undated (Box 93 (Oversize))
  - Drawing for The Atlantic Monthly, 1964 (Box 93 (Oversize))
  - Drawings for House & Garden, undated (Box 93 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings, including some used in Fortune, undated (Box 94 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings, undated; 2 (Box 94 (Oversize))
  - Drawings for LIFE, undated; 2 (Box 94 (Oversize))
  - Drawings of Nixon, 2 (Box 95 (Oversize))
  - Mockup for LOOK, undated (Box 95 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings, undated; 2 (Box 95 (Oversize))
  - Flight safety posters, undated (Box 95 (Oversize))
  - Correspondence and clippings, undated (Box 96 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings, undated; 2 (Box 96 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings, undated; 3 (Box 97 (Oversize))
  - "Streep" drawings, undated (Box 98 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated (Box 98 (Oversize))
  - "The Sleepwalkers" for The New Republic, 1966 (Box 98 (Oversize))
  - Drawings for Mike Straights' Trial by Television, undated (Box 99 (Oversize))
  - "Architect and Client", undated (Box 99 (Oversize))
  - Drawings for True Magazine, undated (Box 99 (Oversize))
  - Drawing for Reports on Research, undated (Box 99 (Oversize))
  - Drawing for The Architectural Forum, undated (Box 99 (Oversize))
  - Originals and overlays for "War is No Damn Good", 1946-1947; 2 (Box 100 (Oversize))
  - Osborn works for various exhibits, 1963, undated; 2 (Box 101 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified Drawings, undated; 4 (Box 102 (Oversize))
  - Drawings for Horticulture, undated (Box 103 (Oversize))
  - Drawings sent to Houghton Mifflin Company, 3 (Box 103 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings, undated; 2 (Box 103 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings, undated; 2 (Box 104 (Oversize))
  - Drawings sent to the Heckscher Museum, undated (Box 104 (Oversize))
  - "Rule by Terror (Bomb)," drawings sent to The New Republic, 1963 (Box 104 (Oversize))
  - "Anger," drawings sent to The Saturday Evening Post, 1963 (Box 104 (Oversize))
  - "Limericks," drawings sent to Doubleday and Company, 1963 (Box 104 (Oversize))
  - Drawings sent to Naval Aviation News, undated (Box 104 (Oversize))
  - Drawings send to LOOK magazine, undated (Box 104 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified painting, undated (Box 105 (Oversize))
  - "Robert Frost", undated (Box 106 (Oversize))
  - "String Quartette", undated (Box 106 (Oversize))
  - "Carl Sandberg" and "Tchaikovsky" (Box 106 (Oversize))
  - Industrial posters, 1949-1950 (Box 106 (Oversize))
  - Drawings sent to The New Republic, 1967 (Box 106 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated; 2 (Box 107 (Oversize))
  - "Benjamin Britton", undated (Box 108 (Oversize))
  - "Rilke", undated (Box 108 (Oversize))
  - "Milton", undated (Box 108 (Oversize))
  - "Wagner", undated (Box 108 (Oversize))
  - 'The Enormous Room", undated (Box 108 (Oversize))
  - "Liszt", undated (Box 109 (Oversize))
  - "The Lowells", undated (Box 109 (Oversize))
  - "Hindemith", undated (Box 109 (Oversize))
  - "W. H. Auden", 1974 (Box 109 (Oversize))
  - "Mussorgsky", undated (Box 109 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings, undated (Box 110 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings, undated; 3 (Box 111 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings, undated (Box 112 (Oversize))
  - Drawings sent to AOPA Air Safety Foundation, 1991 (Box 112 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings, undated; 3 (Box 113 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings, undated; 2 (Box 114 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings, undated; 2 (Box 115 (Oversize))
  - "Zero Mostel as Rhinoceros", 1968 (Box 116 (Oversize))
  - "Sea Sickness" and "Power Lines Along the Missouri", 1957-1959 (Box 116 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings, undated (Box 116 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated; 3 (Box 117 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated; 2 (Box 118 (Oversize))
  - "Ah! Those Light Planes!" and "Plant Lover", undated (Box 119 (Oversize))
  - "Plant Breeder" and "Pollution", undated (Box 119 (Oversize))
  - "We Have Nothing Much to Conceal" and "Cesar Franck", undated (Box 119 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings, undated; 3 (Box 120 (Oversize))
  - Sketch notebook, undated (Box 121 (Oversize))
  - Dilbert drawings, undated; 4 (Box 121 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings, undated; 8 (Box 122 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated; 9 (Box 123 (Oversize))
  - Drawing for Telephone Review, 1964 (Box 124 (Oversize))
  - Drawings for Naval Aviation News, 1963 (Box 124 (Oversize))
  - Drawings for War/Peace Report, 1967 (Box 124 (Oversize))
  - Fortune delegation of authority, undated (Box 124 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings, undated; 4 (Box 124 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated; 5 (Box 125 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings, undated (Box 126 (Oversize))
  - "Automation", undated (Box 126 (Oversize))
  - Drawings for LOOK, undated (Box 126 (Oversize))
  - Drawings for Telephone Review, 1966 (Box 126 (Oversize))
  - Drawings for The New Republic, 1966 (Box 126 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings, undated; 2 (Box 127 (Oversize))
  - "Dollar Bag Uncle Sam" and "Grow", 1960, undated (Box 128 (Oversize))
  - "Bomber", 1975 (Box 128 (Oversize))
  - "J. Blake", 1974 (Box 128 (Oversize))
  - "Puritan," "Levasseur Antoinette," "Brahms," "Dyaln Thomas", undated (Box 129 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings, undated; 4 (Box 130 (Oversize))
  - Drawings for IBM, 1962 (Box 130 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings, undated; 5 (Box 130 (Oversize))
  - "Allergies", undated (Box 130 (Oversize))
  - "Big Business", undated (Box 131 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings, undated; 2 (Box 131 (Oversize))
  - Drawings for the American Federation of Teachers, undated (Box 131 (Oversize))
  - Drawings for Arnold Newman, undated (Box 131 (Oversize))
  - Drawings for The New Republic, 1963 (Box 131 (Oversize))
  - State Department Book, undated (Box 131 (Oversize))
  - Drawings for Henry Straus, 1959 (Box 131 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings, undated (Box 131 (Oversize))
  - Drawings for LOOK, 1963 (Box 131 (Oversize))
  - First Dilbert poster sketches, 1942-1943 (Box 132 (Oversize))
  - Drawings for the Association of Naval Aviation, undated (Box 132 (Oversize))
  - Drawings for Naval Aviation News, 1994 (Box 132 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawing, undated (Box 133 (Oversize))
  - "D.A.R." and "Devastation Along the Missouri", 1960 (Box 133 (Oversize))
  - "The Way Mendelsohn's Music Feels to Me" and "Horn Player", 1969, 1961 (Box 133 (Oversize))
  - "Man Has Always Yearned to Fly", 1975 (Box 133 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings, undated (Box 134 (Oversize))
  - Drawings for the Saturday Evening Post, 1966 (Box 134 (Oversize))
  - Drawings for The Atlantic, 1962; 2 (Box 134 (Oversize))
  - "Vincent d'Indy", undated (Box 135 (Oversize))
  - "Burgundy", 1929 (Box 135 (Oversize))
  - "String Quartette", undated (Box 135 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings, undated; 3 (Box 136 (Oversize))
  - "R.O by R.O.," "Baloonatics," and "The Start of Problems", 1969, 1975 (Box 137 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings and paintings, undated; 5 (Box 138 (Oversize))
  - "Middle Aged", undated (Box 139 (Oversize))
  - Drawings for Houghton Mifflin Company, 1969 (Box 140 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings, undated (Box 140 (Oversize))
  - Drawings for Capper Publications, 1955 (Box 141 (Oversize))
  - Drawings for Trans-action, 1966 (Box 141 (Oversize))
  - Drawings for The New Republic and Harper's Magazine, 1963, 1966 (Box 141 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings, undated; 5 (Box 142 (Oversize))
  - Drawings for Fortune, 1962 (Box 143 (Oversize))
  - Drawings of Charlie Chaplin, undated (Box 143 (Oversize))
  - "Faces", undated (Box 143 (Oversize))
  - Drawings for The New Republic, 1965 (Box 144 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified drawings, undated (Box 144 (Oversize))
  - Drawings for Ted Mills and IBM, 1967 (Box 145 (Oversize))
  - Drawings of senses, undated (Box 145 (Oversize))
  - Drawings for Naval Aviation News, 1966 (Box 145 (Oversize))
  - Drawings for The New Republic, 1965 (Box 145 (Oversize))